

## **MEHWISH TAUQIR**

**Permanent Address:** House # 1033-A, Block E, Canal View Housing Society, Lahore.

Mobile: +92-322-4936463 E-mail: mehwishtauqir@gmail.com

Passionate preschool teacher with 3 years of work experience and proven record of improving assessment scores. Worked as lead teacher, commended by colleagues for work ethics and warm personality. Skilled in patience, communication and classroom management.

#### **SKILLS**

- Early Childhood Education.
- Curriculum Development.
- Growth Portfolios.
- Creative Lesson Planning.

- Cooperative and Experiential Learning.
- Creative Mindset.
- Classroom Management.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### September 2018 - Present NATIONAL GRAMMAR PRE-SCHOOL, LAHORE.

### **Preparatory Class Teacher**

- Lead classroom Lead preschool teacher, 5-6 years old classroom.
- Facilitate classroom activities and circle time.
- Motivating and stimulating children's public speaking abilities.
- Maintain the complete records of students.
- Introduce children to discipline and the importance of following rule.
- Prepare and present effective lessons within the curriculum guidelines, using proper tools and helping aid.
- Attend and contribute to staff meetings and parent teacher conferences.

- Update teaching resource and classroom environment accordance with monthly theme.
- Participate in school's extra-curricular events.

# April 2017 - Present NATIONAL GRAMMAR PRE-SCHOOL, LAHORE.

## Reception (Nursery) Class Teacher

- Prepare and implement lesson plan to classroom averaging 15 students of 4-5 years old.
- Conducted circle time and oracy.
- Maintain the complete records of students.
- Prepare and present effective lessons within the curriculum guidelines, using proper tools and helping aid.
- Frequent contact with parents to discuss student's behavior and development.
- Update teaching resource and classroom environment accordance with theme.
- Participate in school's extra-curricular events like welcome/farewell party, farewell, open-house session for project display, excursion trips etc.

## Jan 2016- Feb 2017 GREAT BEGINNINGS SCHOOL SYSTEM, ISLAMABAD

## Montessori (Nursery) Teacher

- Conducting group activities.
- Maintaining the complete records of students.
- Prepare lesson plans and methods of assessment.
- Prepare and present effective lessons within the curriculum guidelines, using proper tools and helping aid.
- Attend and contribute to staff meetings, parent teacher conferences, celebrations, workshops and special events.
- Decorating the class in accordance with the theme.
- Organize different extra-curricular activities like Montessori graduation ceremony, school trips, etc.

#### **EDUCATION**

### 2010-2012 National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences-FAST

Masters in Business Administration

- Major in Marketing
- CGPA 3.07

## 2005 - 2010 COMSATS INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Bachelor in Business Administration [BS (BA)]

- Major in Marketing
- Got 75.74% with CGPA 2.98

## 2003 - 2005 KINNAIRD COLLEGE FOR WOMEN UN IVERSITY

• Humanities Group

### TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Microsoft Office (Word, Power Point, Excel)

### **PERSONALITY**

- Devoted towards the task, quick learner.
- Capable of meeting deadlines.
- Punctual, hard working, flexible.
- Team player.

### **EXTRA - CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

- Member of dramatic society in school
- Two certificates for organizing and participating in Convocation by COMSATS, Lahore
- Voluntary arranged stalls for charity in Kinnaird College for Women, Lahore and National University for Computer and Emerging Sciences (FAST)

### **LANGUAGES**

• Can speak & write **English**, **Urdu**, and **French** (basics) fluently.